Finding Aid for Nathan W. Shock Papers 1906-1989
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Correspondence
  - Halsell, G., 1974-1976 (Box 8)
  - Hamlin, R.M., 1985 (Box 8)
  - Hamm, W.J., 1978 (Box 8)
  - Hankinson, R., 1976 (Box 8)
  - Hanna, P.T., 1976 (Box 8)
  - Hansalik, H.B., 1976 (Box 8)
  - Hansson, L., 1985 (Box 8)
  - Hard, W., 1947 (Box 8)
  - Harman, D., 1981 (Box 8)
  - Harman, S.M., 1976 (Box 8)
  - Harris, M.I., 1976 (Box 8)
  - Harris, R., 1975 (Box 8)
  - Harrison, D.E., 1984 (Box 8)
  - Harrison, H.E., 1975 (Box 8)
  - Hartz, A., 1985 (Box 8)
  - Harvey, J.C., 1976 (Box 8)
  - Hastings, A.B., 1958-1987 (Box 8)
  - Hastings, A.B., Jr., 1988 (Box 8)
  - Havighurst, R.J., 1975 (Box 8)
  - Hayflick, L., 1964-1988 (Box 8)
  - Head, Cardiovascular Section, 1976 (Box 8)
  - Head, Technical Development Section, 1976 (Box 8)
  - Heaney, R., 1976 (Box 8)
  - Hedrich, R., 1976 (Box 8)
  - Heller, B.R., 1976 (Box 8)
  - Hendee, W.R., 1979 (Box 8)
  - Henry, P.J., 1982 (Box 8)
  - Hershey, D., 1978-1982 (Box 8)
  - Hettinger, W.P., Jr., 1974-1982 (Box 8)
  - Hewick, D.S., 1976 (Box 8)
  - Heylin, M., 1978 (Box 8)
  - High, E.W., 1976 (Box 8)
  - Hijmans, W., 1978 (Box 8)
  - Hines, (n.i.), 1976 (Box 8)
  - Hirsch, G., 1976 (Box 8)
  - Hirsh, J., 1977 (Box 8)
  - Hochschild, R., 1976 (Box 8)
  - Hoepfner, R., 1976 (Box 8)
  - Hoffman, P.B., 1984 (Box 8)
  - Hollander, C.F., 1976-1977 (Box 8)
  - Holt, P.R., 1983-1984 (Box 8)
  - Hopps, H.C., 1976 (Box 8)
  - Howard, M.O., 1976 (Box 8)
  - Hrusa, Z., 1960-1972 (Box 8)
  - Hubbard, F.G., 1962-1976 (Box 8)
  - Hunter, J., 1977 (Box 8)
  - Hurvitz, S.A., 1976 (Box 8)
  - Inall, R.J., 1976 (Box 9)
  - Indira Sriram, K., 1979 (Box 9)
  - Information Officer, National Institute on Aging, 1976 (Box 9)
  - Ingelfinger, F.J., 1975 (Box 9)
  - Institute of Gerontology, University of Michigan, 1976 (Box 9)
  - Jackson, D.J., 1976 (Box 9)
  - Jakubczak, L.F., 1976 (Box 9)
  - Jensen, W.A., 1978 (Box 9)
  - Jerath, B.K., 1976 (Box 9)
  - Johnson, H.R., 1978-1979 (Box 9)
  - Johnson, M., 1976 (Box 9)
  - Johnson, R., 1976 (Box 9)
  - Jones, E.J., 1977 (Box 9)
  - Jones, R.L., 1985 (Box 9)
  - Jordan, L.M., 1979 (Box 9)
  - Journal of Nervous and Mental Disease, 1977 (Box 9)
  - Joy, T., 1976 (Box 9)
  - Kahn, R., 1976 (Box 9)
  - Kalish, R.A., 1979 (Box 9)
  - Kaplan, J., 1974-1988 (Box 9)
  - Kaplan, O.J., 1975-1985 (Box 9)
  - Kaplan, S.M., 1974 (Box 9)
  - Kaskowitz, E., 1974-1976 (Box 9)
  - Kastenbaum, R.J., 1978 (Box 9)
  - Katzman, R., 1976 (Box 9)
  - Kavaler, F., 1976 (Box 9)
  - Kay, M.M.B, 1974-1976 (Box 9)
  - Kearney, J., 1978 (Box 9)
  - Kebabian, J., 1975 (Box 9)
  - Khan, M.H., 1975 (Box 9)
  - Kirch berger, M., 1976 (Box 9)
  - Kline, O.L., 1976 (Box 9)
  - Klumpp, T.G., 1976 (Box 9)
  - Knittweis, J.W., 1976 (Box 9)
  - Knook, R.L., 1976 (Box 9)
  - Knutti, R.E., 1963 (Box 9)
  - Kodandapani, S., 1975-1976 (Box 9)
  - Kokkonen, G., 1976-1985 (Box 9)
  - Koladycz, D., 1976 (Box 9)
  - Kopelke, C.E., 1976 (Box 9)
  - Kostelc, J., 1979 (Box 9)
  - Kretchmer, N., 1974 (Box 9)
  - Kuhne, B., 1975 (Box 9)
  - Kuplan, L., 1984-1986 (Box 9)
  - Kurashvili, R., 1976 (Box 9)
  - Kurlychek, R.T., 1976 (Box 9)
  - Kurtz, A.K., 1985 (Box 9)
  - Kushner, R.E., 1959-1966 (Box 9)
  - Kutsky, R., 1976 (Box 9)
  - La Bella, F.S., 1986 (Box 9)
  - Laddis, (n.i.), 1976 (Box 9)
  - Laird, T.A., 1983 (Box 9)
  - Lakatta, E.G., 1974-1976 (Box 9)
  - Lamberg, S.I., 1976 (Box 9)
  - Landry, (n.i.), 1976 (Box 9)
  - Langfitt, T.W., 1976-1977 (Box 9)
  - Lansing, A.I., 1985 (Box 9)
  - Lappe, D.L., 1976 (Box 9)
  - Lascalea, M.C., 1974 (Box 9)
  - Lasker, Mrs. A.D., 1976 (Box 9)
  - Lee, M., 1979 (Box 9)
  - Lefkowitz, R.J., 1976 (Box 9)
  - Lemp, H., 1974 (Box 9)
  - Lennox, T.G., 1976 (Box 9)
  - Lessin, P.J., 1976 (Box 9)
  - Levi, L., 1974 (Box 9)
  - Levine, S.S., 1979 (Box 9)
  - Libbers, M., 1976 (Box 9)
  - Linch, F., 1986 (Box 9)
  - Lindegren, R., 1976 (Box 9)
  - Lindeman, R.D., 1981-1987 (Box 9)
  - Littleboy, J., 1978 (Box 9)
  - Lockett, B., 1978 (Box 9)
  - Loeb, L., 1976 (Box 9)
  - Longino, C.F., Jr., 1979 (Box 9)
  - Lowe, (n.i.), 1974 (Box 9)
  - Luchmann, D., 1986 (Box 9)
  - Lumpkin, C.K., Jr., 1976 (Box 9)
  - Lumsden, B., 1976 (Box 9)
  - McCay, O., 1968-1970 (Box 9)
  - McCormick, G., 1976 (Box 9)
  - MacDonell, J.A., 1976 (Box 9)
  - MacDonough, C., 1984 (Box 9)
  - McLintock, M.K., 1979 (Box 9)
  - McPherson, A.T., 1975 (Box 9)
  - Maddox, G.L., Jr., 1974-1987 (Box 9)
  - Mahoney, F.S., 1976 (Box 9)
  - Makinodan, T., 1976 (Box 9)
  - Maklan, C.W., 1979 (Box 9)
  - Mann, P., 1976 (Box 9)
  - Margulec, I., 1972 (Box 9)
  - Marois, M., 1975-1976 (Box 9)
  - Maryland Department of Economic and Community Development, 1976 (Box 9)
  - Maryland Gerontological Association, 1985 (Box 9)
  - Massie, H., 1987 (Box 9)
  - Mayerson, H.S., 1976 (Box 9)
  - Meade, G.M., 1976 (Box 9)
  - Medvedev, Z.A., 1958-1984 (Box 9)
  - Melrose, R.J., 1976 (Box 9)
  - Melville, S.D., 1976 (Box 9)
  - Menkes, H., 1976 (Box 9)
  - Merril, C.R., 1976 (Box 9)
  - Metzger, N., 1978 (Box 9)
  - Mickelson, O., 1978 (Box 9)
  - Midwest Authors' Guild, 1977 (Box 9)
  - Miller, E.H., 1976 (Box 9)
  - Moe, G.K., 1976 (Box 9)
  - Mohler, S.R., 1980 (Box 9)
  - Moment, G., 1975-1976 (Box 9)
  - Morales, M.F., 1980-1984 (Box 9)
  - Morehead, J., 1976 (Box 9)
  - Moseley, R., 1978 (Box 9)
  - Moulton, C., 1979 (Box 9)
  - Moye, E., 1977 (Box 9)
  - Munan, L., 1978 (Box 9)
  - Murakami, M., 1979-1985 (Box 9)
  - Murphy, D.G., 1976 (Box 9)
  - Myburgh, J.A., 1978 (Box 9)
  - Mysliwski, A., 1978 (Box 9)
  - Nall, R., 1976 (Box 9)
  - National Council on the Aging (NCOA), 1984-1988 (Box 9)
  - Neugarten, B.L., 1975-1985 (Box 9)
  - Newman, E.S., 1976 (Box 9)
  - Nichols, H.B., 1965 (Box 9)
  - Nordin, A.A., 1976 (Box 9)
  - Norris, A.H., 1976 (Box 9)
  - Obrist, (n.i.), 1979 (Box 9)
  - Ochi, H., 1987 (Box 9)
  - Oepen, H., 1977 (Box 9)
  - Oh, (n.i.), 1976 (Box 9)
  - Olsen, J.K., 1978 (Box 9)
  - Olson, J., 1976 (Box 9)
  - Omachi, C., 1987 (Box 9)
  - O'Malley, K., 1976 (Box 9)
  - Orbach, E., 1984 (Box 9)
  - Orbach, H.L., 1976 (Box 9)
  - Orimo, H., 1985 (Box 9)
  - Orloff, J., 1976 (Box 9)
  - Ossofsky, J., 1984-1988 (Box 9)
  - Owellen, R.J., 1976 (Box 9)
  - Park, M.C., 1984 (Box 9)
  - Parker, R.J., 1976 (Box 9)
  - Passwater, R.A., 1970 (Box 9)
  - Pasternack, R.F., 1974 (Box 9)
  - Patrick, G.P., 1988 (Box 9)
  - Patterson, J.E., 1976 (Box 9)
  - Peabody, R., 1976 (Box 9)
  - Pearlin, L., 1976 (Box 9)
  - Penman, R., 1976 (Box 9)
  - Pepper, C., 1987 (Box 9)
  - Perreboom, T., 1978 (Box 9)
  - Personnel Specialist, 1976 (Box 9)
  - Peter Bent Brigham Hospital, 1976 (Box 9)
  - Peterson, A.M., 1976 (Box 9)
  - Peterson, W.T., 1976 (Box 9)
  - Peters-Snow, N.P., 1976 (Box 9)
  - Pierce, N.F., 1976 (Box 9)
  - Pilgeram, L.O., 1977 (Box 9)
  - Pisha, B.V., 1976-1977 (Box 9)
  - Pitcairn, D.M., 1976 (Box 9)
  - Pittendrigh, C.S., 1976 (Box 9)
  - Plotz, J., 1976 (Box 9)
  - Polgar, P., 1976 (Box 9)
  - Pollard, J.H., 1978 (Box 9)
  - POPLINE, 1976 (Box 9)
  - Porter, S., 1976 (Box 9)
  - Preston, J.B., 1976 (Box 9)
  - Pritikin, N., 1974-1976 (Box 9)
  - Public Health Reports, 1976 (Box 9)
  - Publications Committee, 1973-1974 (Box 9)
  - Quilter, (n.i.), 1976 (Box 9)
  - Quinn, B., 1979 (Box 9)
  - Quinn, P., 1947 (Box 9)
  - Ragonesi, R., 1974 (Box 9)
  - Rall, D.P., 1976 (Box 9)
  - Ramsey, R.W., 1960 (Box 9)
  - Randall, O., 1974-1985 (Box 9)
  - Rapoport, S., 1984 (Box 9)
  - Rappoport, S.I., 1976 (Box 9)
  - Rauscher, F.J., Jr., 1976 (Box 9)
  - Reichel, W., 1975-1987 (Box 10)
  - Reife, T.R., 1971-1975 (Box 10)
  - Riley, M.W., 1975-1976 (Box 10)
  - Robertson, E., 1974 (Box 10)
  - Rockstein, M., 1982-1986 (Box 10)
  - Rodale Press, 1976 (Box 10)
  - Rogers, D., 1982-1984 (Box 10)
  - Root, M.T., 1975 (Box 10)
  - Ross, G., 1974 (Box 10)
  - Ross, H.K., 1976 (Box 10)
  - Ross, R., 1975-1976 (Box 10)
  - Ross, S.S., 1976 (Box 10)
  - Rothbaum, D., 1978 (Box 10)
  - Rothstein, M., 1986 (Box 10)
  - Rowles, G.D., 1979 (Box 10)
  - Rundell, J.O., 1976 (Box 10)
  - Rusk, G.Y., 1953-1963 (Box 10)
  - Russek, H.J., 1976 (Box 10)
  - Rust, D.A., 1974 (Box 10)
  - Rutherford, W.L., 1965 (Box 10)
  - Sabbeth, S.G., 1979 (Box 10)
  - Sacher, G.A., 1974-1984 (Box 10)
  - Sacktor, (n.i.), 1976 (Box 10)
  - Salans, L., 1976 (Box 10)
  - Samis, H., Jr., 1978 (Box 10)
  - Schaie, K.W., 1981-1987 (Box 10)
  - Schechter, M., 1987 (Box 10)
  - Schmeck, H., 1979 (Box 10)
  - Schmid, P., 1976 (Box 10)
  - Schneider, E.L., 1976-1984 (Box 10)
  - Schuster, M.M., 1976 (Box 10)
  - Schweinhaut, M., 1975 (Box 10)
  - Science, 1976 (Box 10)
  - Scientific Director, 1974 (Box 10)
  - Scott, Mrs. J.R., 1976 (Box 10)
  - Sears, R., 1978 (Box 10)
  - Shanas, E., 1974-1976 (Box 10)
  - Shannon, J.A., 1983 (Box 10)
  - Sheraton Centre, 1976 (Box 10)
  - Sherman, E.D., 1984 (Box 10)
  - Shin, (n.i.), 1976 (Box 10)
  - Shore, H., 1976 (Box 10)
  - Sidman, C.F., 1985 (Box 10)
  - Silbert, J.E., 1977-1983 (Box 10)
  - Sinclair, U., 1963-1964 (Box 10)
  - Sinex, F.M., 1975-1976 (Box 10)
  - Singer, L., 1976 (Box 10)
  - Skinner, B.F., 1983 (Box 10)
  - Sluss, T.K., 1979-1981 (Box 10)
  - Smerling, B., 1977 (Box 10)
  - Smith, D., 1976 (Box 10)
  - Smith, James, 1976 (Box 10)
  - Smith, Jeffrey K., 1979 (Box 10)
  - Smith, L., 1976 (Box 10)
  - Society for Experimental Biology and Medicine, 1984-1987 (Box 10)
  - Solomon, N., 1977 (Box 10)
  - Solon, (n.i.), 1976 (Box 10)
  - Special Assistant to Associate Director for Program Planning and Evaluation, National Institute on Aging, 1976 (Box 10)
  - Springer, U., 1985-1987 (Box 10)
  - Spurgeon, H.A., 1978 (Box 10)
  - Stadtman, E.R., 1983 (Box 10)
  - Stamler, J., 1965 (Box 10)
  - Standish, R., 1976 (Box 10)
  - Steel, R.K., 1982 (Box 10)
  - Stevenson, I.H., 1978 (Box 10)
  - Stewart, M.S., 1947 (Box 10)
  - Stoltzner, G., 1976 (Box 10)
  - Streeter, D.D., 1978 (Box 10)
  - Strehler, B.L., 1971-1988; 4 folders (Box 10)
  - Streib, G.F., 1976 (Box 10)
  - Supervisor, A.R.F., Gerontology Research Center, 1976 (Box 10)
  - Talbot, B., 1975 (Box 10)
  - Tan, (n.i.), 1975 (Box 10)
  - Tarien, (n.i.), 1976 (Box 10)
  - Tauchi, H., 1976 (Box 10)
  - Templeton, G.H., 1975-1976 (Box 10)
  - Thomae, H., 1984-1985 (Box 10)
  - Thompson, L.W., 1976 (Box 10)
  - Thornton, S., 1976 (Box 10)
  - Tibbin, M.P., 1976 (Box 10)
  - Tobin, J.D., 1981 (Box 10)
  - Toll, J., 1980 (Box 10)
  - University Park Press, 1976 (Box 10)
  - Van Rooy, (n.i.), 1976 (Box 10)
  - Van Zonneveld, R.J., 1976 (Box 10)
  - Vanderhoek, J.Y., 1976 (Box 10)
  - Verzar, F., 1958-1983 (Box 10)
  - Veterans Administration, Aging Research, 1960-1984 (Box 10)
  - Von Hahn, H.P., 1983-1986 (Box 10)
  - Walcher, D.N., 1978-1979 (Box 10)
  - Walford, R.L., 1982-1983 (Box 10)
  - Wang Chih Tung, 1981 (Box 10)
  - Wang Huan Pao, 1985 (Box 10)
  - Warder, M.Y., 1976 (Box 10)
  - Waters, J.A., 1976 (Box 10)
  - Watkin, D.M., 1975-1978 (Box 10)
  - W.B. Saunders Co., 1976 (Box 10)
  - Weaver, K.H., 1979 (Box 10)
  - Weisberg, S.M., 1976 (Box 10)
  - Weisfeldt, M.L., 1975-1976 (Box 10)
  - Weiss, A.K., 1984-1987 (Box 10)
  - Weissfeld, J., 1978 (Box 10)
  - Weksler, M.E., 1976 (Box 10)
  - Wekstein, D.R., 1975 (Box 10)
  - Welford, A., 1976-1986 (Box 10)
  - White, S., 1976 (Box 10)
  - Williams, H., 1975 (Box 10)
  - Williams, T.F., 1984-1985 (Box 10)
  - Williams, W.E., 1976 (Box 10)
  - Winkler, S., 1976 (Box 10)
  - Winograd, C., 1980-1981 (Box 10)
  - Wollitzer, A.O., 1977 (Box 10)
  - Wozniak, R.HG., 1985 (Box 10)
  - Yin, F.C.P., 1975 (Box 10)
  - Youngdahl, J., 1987 (Box 10)
  - Zavagli, G., 1975 (Box 10)
  - Zay, N., 1976 (Box 10)
  - Zelle, M.R., 1976 (Box 10)
  - Zs.-Nagy, I., 1983 (Box 10)
  - Zuckerman, B.M., 1976 (Box 10)
- Gerontology Research Center, 1940-1978
  The Gerontology Research Center, an active research facility under the National Institutes of Health, was headed by Shock from 1941 to 1978, at the Baltimore City Hospitals. The arrangement of this series is largely chronological or topical where required for clarity. An important subseries here is the papers of the Baltimore Longitudinal Study of Aging (3 linear feet); it includes information on the recruitment of the first patient into the study in 1957 until the celebration of the 30th anniversary of the study in 1988.
  - Administrative files
    - Edward J. Steiglitz papers, 1939-1941
      - Conference on Mental Health in Later Maturity, Washington, May 23-24, 1941 (Box 11)
      - Conference on Prophylactic Geriatrics for Defense, 1941 (Box 11)
      - National Advisory Committee on Gerontology, 1940-1942 (Box 11)
      - Members, National Advisory Committee on Gerontology, 1940 (Box 11)
      - First Meeting, National Advisory Committee on Gerontology, November 25-26, 1940 (Box 11)
      - Research proposals, 1940-1941 (Box 11)
      - Correspondence, 1941 (Box 11)
      - Speeches, 1941 (Box 11)
    - Administrative papers, miscellaneous, 1946-1951 (Box 11)
    - Aging projects for review, 1958-1963 (Box 11)
    - Memorandum on aging program activities prepared for Under-Secretary of United States Department of Health, Education and Welfare, Wilbur J. Cohen, 1966 (Box 11)
    - "Smith Committee Report", Special Program (Box 11)
    - Planning Committee, National Institute of Child Health and Human Development, June 1966 (Box 11)
    - National Institute of Child Health and Human Development Report to the President, 1966 (Box 11)
    - Johnson, Howard A., Administrative Officer, Gerontology Research Center, 1967-1969 (Box 11)
    - Program statements, Gerontology Research Center, 1969-1974 (Box 11)
    - Legislative history, 1964-1969 (Box 11)
    - Senate Special Committee on Aging (Duncan Report)
      - 1969-1970 (Box 11)
      - Background material, 1965-1970 (Box 11)
    - Gerontology Research Center alumni, 1975 (Box 12)
    - Gerontology Research Center administrative files, 1970-1971 (Box 12)
    - Gerontology Research Center administrative files, 1972-1973 (Box 12)
    - Administration on Aging, Department of Health, Education and Welfare, 1963-1969
      - Administration on Aging, "Designs for action for older Americans", 1967-1969 (Box 12)
      - Administration on Aging, "Federal financial assistance for projects in aging", 1967-1968 (Box 12)
    - Special report on aging for House Appropriations Subcommittee, 1974 (Box 12)
    - Labor-management agreement, Gerontology Research Center and American Federation of Government Employees, 1976 (Box 12)
    - Reports on Aging, National Institutes of Health, 1974 (Box 12)
  - Annual reports, 1940-1978
    - 1940-1943 (Box 12)
    - 1945 (Box 12)
    - 1947-1948 (Box 12)
    - 1949 (Box 12)
    - 1952 (Box 12)
    - 1952-1956 (Box 12)
      (studies in progress)
    - 1953 (Box 12)
    - 1954 (Box 12)
    - 1955 (Box 12)
    - 1956 (Box 12)
    - 1957 (Box 12)
    - 1958 (Box 12)
    - 1959 (Box 12)
    - 1960 (Box 12)
    - 1961 (Box 12)
    - 1962 (Box 12)
    - January 1963-June 1964 (Box 12)
    - July 1964-June 1965 (Box 12)
    - July 1965-June 1966 (Box 12)
    - July 1966-June 1967 (Box 13)
    - July 1967-June 1968 (Box 13)
    - July 1968-June 1969 (Box 13)
    - July 1969-June 1970 (Box 13)
    - July 1970-June 1971 (Box 13)
    - July 1971-June 1972 (Box 13)
    - July 1972-June 1973 (Box 13)
    - July 1973-June 1974 (Box 13)
    - July 1974-June 1975 (Box 13)
    - July 1975-June 1976 (Box 13)
    - July 1976-September 1977 (Box 13)
    - October 1977-September 1978 (Box 13)
    - Annual reports, Guest Scientist Program, April 1976-March 1977 (Box 13)
  - Budget and operating plans
    - 1941-1949 (Box 13)
      (incomplete)
    - July-December 1949 (Box 13)
    - 1949-1950 (Box 13)
    - 1950 (Box 13)
    - January-June 1950 (Box 13)
    - 1954 (Box 13)
    - 1956 (Box 14)
    - 1957 (Box 14)
    - 1958-1961 (Box 14)
    - 1966 (Box 14)
    - 1968-1969 (Box 14)
    - 1970 (Box 14)
    - 1971 (Box 14)
    - 1972 (Box 14)
    - 1973-1974 (Box 14)
    - 1975 (Box 14)
    - 1976, 2 folders (Box 14)
    - 1977, 2 folders (Box 14)
    - 1978 (Box 14)
  - Staff
    - 1947-1955 (Box 14)
    - 1956-1965 (Box 14)
    - 1962-1963 (Box 14)
    - 1965-1966 (Box 14)
    - 1967-1971 (Box 15)
    - 1968-1969 (Box 15)
    - 1971 (Box 15)
    - 1972 (Box 15)
    - 1973 (Box 15)
    - 1974 (Box 15)
    - 1975 (Box 15)
    - 1976 (Box 15)
    - 1977 (Box 15)
    - Staff projections, 1958-1976 (Box 15)
    - Staff promotions, 1969-1975 (Box 15)
    - Staff salary scales, 1948-1976 (Box 15)
  - Research
    - Research projects, program statements
      - 1951 (Box 15)
      - 1952 (Box 15)
      - 1957 (Box 15)
      - 1959-1963 (Box 15)
      - 1969 (Box 15)
      - 1974 (Box 15)
      - 1975 (Box 15)
    - Opportunities for research on aging, 1974 (Box 16)
    - Research highlights
      - 1965-1966 (Box 16)
      - 1967 (Box 16)
      - 1968 (Box 16)
      - 1970 (Box 16)
      - 1971 (Box 16)
    - Research evaluation; research fraud, 1982 (Box 16)
    - Research reports
      - Baker, S.P., 1954-1969 (Box 16)
      - Birren, J.E., 1947-1951; 3 folders (Box 16)
      - Davies, D.F., 1947-1948 (Box 16)
      - Duncan, L.E., Jr., 1949-1951 (Box 16)
      - Falzone, J.A., 1953-1957 (Box 16)
      - Gregerman, R.I., 1955-1970 (Box 16)
      - Hettinger, W.P., 1965-1975; 2 folders (Box 16)
      - Landowne, M., 1949-1957 (Box 16)
      - Lowe, C.U., 1969-1970; 2 folders (Box 16)
      - Norris, A.H., 1954-1955 (Box 16)
      - Reichel, W., 1966-1972 (Box 16)
      - Silverstone, F.A., 1953-1957 (Box 16)
      - Solomon, D.H., 1948-1950 (Box 17)
      - Solomon, N., 1962-1972; 2 folders (Box 17)
      - Strehler, B.L., 1956-1972; 4 folders (Box 17)
      - Watkin, D.M., 1950-1954 (Box 17)
      - Weisfeldt, M.L., 1967-1977 (Box 17)
      - Gerontology Discussion Group, 1954-1958 (Box 17)
    - Research Programs, Studies, Ideas
      - Research ideas, general, 1940-1977 (Box 17)
      - Research ideas, psychology, 1940-1967; 2 folders (Box 17)
      - Research ideas, topical, A, 1940-1959 (Box 17)
      - Research ideas, topical, ACTH, 1940-1959 (Box 17)
      - Research ideas, topical, B, 1940-1959 (Box 17)
      - Research ideas, topical, C, 1940-1959 (Box 18)
      - Research ideas, topical, cardiovascular diseases, 1940-1959 (Box 18)
      - Research ideas, topical, E, 1940-1959 (Box 18)
      - Research ideas, topical, H, 1940-1959 (Box 18)
      - Research ideas, topical, kidney, 1940-1959 (Box 18)
      - Research ideas, topical, L-M, 1940-1959 (Box 18)
      - Research ideas, topical, N-O, 1940-1949 (Box 18)
      - Research ideas, topical, R, 1940-1959 (Box 18)
      - Research ideas, topical, S, 1940-1959 (Box 18)
      - Research methods and procedures, 1940-1959; 3 folders (Box 18)
      - Research programs, 1949-1950 (Box 18)
      - Research programs, 1960-1962
        - Active programs, 1940-1959 (Box 18)
        - Inactive programs, 1940-1959 (Box 18)
        - Baltimore City Hospital Comprehensive Care Program (Box 18)
        - Basic biology (Box 18)
        - Basic science building, 1964 (Box 18)
        - Building program, 1960 (Box 18)
        - Building suggestions, 1960 (Box 18)
        - Coordinators, 1963-1967 (Box 19)
        - Findings and accomplishments, 1941-1960 (Box 19)
        - Miscellaneous programs, 1975-1976 (Box 19)
        - Planned studies, 1940-1959 (Box 19)
        - Projections, 1953-1956 (Box 19)
        - Structure, 1965 (Box 19)
      - Research studies
        - General, 1940-1959 (Box 19)
        - Acid-base (Box 19)
        - Age and drug effects (Box 19)
        - Anoxia (Box 19)
        - Biochemical changes (Box 19)
        - Body water (Box 19)
        - Capillary resistance (Box 19)
        - Carbon dioxide-oxygen (Box 19)
        - Cardiac output (Box 19)
        - Cardiovascular group (Box 19)
        - DNA protocol (Box 19)
        - Enzymes (Box 19)
        - Glutamic acid (Box 19)
        - Height-weight (Box 19)
        - Hernias (Box 19)
        - Hormones (Box 19)
        - Ice (Box 19)
        - Inulin Diodrast (Box 19)
        - Ions, atmospheric (Box 19)
        - Kidney (Box 20)
        - Lysine (Box 20)
        - Metabolism (Box 20)
        - Nutrition (Box 20)
        - Pulse wave velocity (Box 20)
        - Radiation (Box 20)
        - Red cell fragility (Box 20)
        - Renal function (Box 20)
        - Renal function, adolescence (Box 20)
        - Respiratory function (Box 20)
        - Respiratory regulation (Box 20)
  - Office of the Scientific Director, papers
    - 1965-1967 (Box 20)
    - 1968-1969 (Box 20)
    - 1970 (Box 20)
    - 1971 (Box 20)
    - January-June 1972 (Box 20)
    - July-December 1972 (Box 20)
    - 1973 (Box 20)
    - 1974 (Box 20)
    - 1975-1976 (Box 20)
    - Miscellaneous, 1965-1975 (Box 20)
    - Board of Scientific Counselors, 1971-1985 (Box 20)
  - Scientific Branch Chiefs
    - Laboratory animals memoranda, 1969-1975; 3 folders (Box 21)
    - Memoranda, 1974-1976 (Box 21)
    - Staff meetings minutes
      - 1958-1961 (Box 21)
      - 1962-1967 (Box 21)
      - 1968-1969 (Box 21)
      - 1970-1972 (Box 21)
      - 1973 (Box 21)
      - 1974 (Box 21)
      - 1975 (Box 21)
      - 1976 (Box 21)
  - Baltimore Longitudinal Study Of Aging
    - Bibliography of published papers (draft), 1960-1986 (Box 21)
    - Peter, William W., correspondence
      - 1957-June 1958 (Box 21)
      - July-December 1958 (Box 21)
      - 1959-1969 (Box 21)
    - Recruitment of subjects, 1958 (Box 21)
    - Washington Post article, June 16, 1959 (Box 21)
    - Toledo (Ohio) plan, 1959 (Box 21)
    - Scientists' Cliffs organization, 1958-1959 (Box 21)
    - Study subjects' correspondence with W.W. Peters, 1958-1959 (Box 21)
    - Administrative records, 1956-1962 (Box 22)
    - Questionnaires, 1958 (Box 22)
    - Review, 1958-1978 (Box 22)
    - Six S's Newsletter, numbers 1-21; Pages of the Ages, numbers 1-3, 1958-1988 (Box 22)
    - Proposal, circa 1960 (Box 22)
    - First, second, third examination and interview series, 1961 (Box 22)
    - Socioeconomic questionnaire, 1962 (Box 22)
    - Meetings, housekeeping, 1960-1962; 2 folders (Box 22)
    - Nutrition, 1961-1964; 1965-1970; 2 folders (Box 22)
    - Data coding, 1963 (Box 22)
    - Data analysis, 1964-1971 (Box 22)
    - Pathology (autopsy) program, 1963 (Box 22)
    - Roster of subjects, 1959-1965 (Box 22)
    - Study expansion, 1960-1964 (Box 22)
    - Correspondence, 1961-1970; 1971-1977; 2 folders (Box 22)
    - Published reports of studies, 1963-1977 (Box 22)
    - Johns Hopkins School of Public Health Mortality Study, B. Cohen, 1964 (Box 22)
    - Psychological tests, 1964-1967 (Box 22)
    - Renovascular study, 1964-1977 (Box 22)
    - Study meeting, 1964 (Box 22)
    - Extension of study, 1965-1971 (Box 22)
    - Test schedule forms, 1965 (Box 23)
    - Colloquium on Longitudinal Studies, Old Point Comfort, Virginia, February 7-10, 1965 (Box 23)
    - Framingham [Massachusetts] Study Review, 1969 (Box 23)
    - Genetic data, undated (Box 23)
    - Questionnaires evaluation, 1969-1970 (Box 23)
    - Cardiovascular-renal project, 1969-1976 (Box 23)
    - Retirement expectancy study, 1970 (Box 23)
    - Study group meetings
      - 1970-December 1971 (Box 23)
      - January-June 1972 (Box 23)
      - July 1972-June 1973 (Box 23)
      - July 1973-December 1973 (Box 23)
      - 1974 (Box 23)
      - 1975 (Box 23)
      - 1976 (Box 23)
      - 1977 (Box 23)
      - 1978 (Box 23)
      - 1979-1980 (Box 23)
    - Study review committee, 1971-1972 (Box 24)
    - Day-dreaming study, 1972 (Box 24)
    - Renal studies, 1973 (Box 24)
    - History, 1973 (Box 24)
    - Conference on Aging in Women, 1976 (Box 24)
    - Boston Veterans Administration Center, longitudinal studies, 1977-1982 (Box 24)
    - Discussion group, 1982-1988 (Box 24)
    - Miscellaneous, 1983-1988 (Box 24)